The referee in charge of this one is Matthew Carley from England. The stage is set, Leon is ready. New Zealand and Italy in Pulea Rugby World Cup 23.
The first half is set by Paolo Gabisi back there, playing back in the 10 position today, having played second five the other day. Marco Ricciani, really exciting tight head prop.
First chance to build some pressure, some phases, test New Zealand's defence and their discipline. They're full of running and this is the man to do it for them.
First little injection from Ange Kapuahtso. Heavy contact.
Defences good and now Italy have created a little bit of space here. Alam into the line for Ioanni and finds Seb Negri down that right hand channel back.
They come again, look at the phases building early from Italy. New Zealand making a lot of early tackles as Oconee Taylor got it and steals it back.
One by Taylor for New Zealand and now they might look to spread straight away. Ioanni, Ricciani to the iron off line for Munger.
Ricci Munger steps his way through the first, can't get through a second. Good cover defence from Italy.
Now New Zealand get a chance to play and look like they're going to be full of running early. Here's Adi Savi the captain up to halfway.
Odom Barrett up in it first receiver. Aaron Smith again will second man play for Ioanni standing on this outside.
It's a good solid hit from the experienced Luca Morisi. Long opening passage of play here. Scott Barrett carries up over halfway.
And now Aaron Smith has slided some space in behind here for a couple of walks so he finds the touch line.
Wow what a start. A lot of phases, a lot of carries. Both teams showing that they have this interchangeability between the 10s and the 15s.
Both Barrett and Tomas Alen slotting in their first receiver a couple of times. Both coaches will be quite happy with the skill set shown so far.
A lot of phases, a lot of carries. Giacomo Nicotera hasn't missed a line out throw all tournament 18 from 18.
And he's just going to keep that record now as Federico Ruza saves the day but there's a forward pass in there from Italy. A little friendship pressure coming on.
More pressure at the line out. Not clean ball and as a result maybe the little error coming. A little panicky and trying to just set up an opportunity to exit.
And this leaves the All Blacks with a perfect attacking option. 15 metres or so out. This is the line out.
Just tapped back, it's a little scrappy and a little messy and the pressure shifted and that's the forward pass.
Find your spaces, nice and patient.
Santa Scrum.
Moana and Barrett standing right behind the Scrum giving themselves an option to go either way.
Scrum hasn't been a strong suit for New Zealand in the tournament.
Set.
Not to set a platform here, three and a half minutes in.
Not from your side of the Scrum. Go down straight away.
Hey, hey, hey. We'll go across.
Listen, listen guys, both sides are talking to each other.
Coming up ever so slightly under that first Scrum pressure.
Patient for each call, okay? Scrummage over the mark, both sides.
I know, I gave you time.
So the line up's changed now. The Scrum having moved five or six metres to the right.
Biden and Barrett's gone to the left.
Moana to the right.
You fancy they'll go with a wheel.
Chamberway, the Scrum wheels, you'd think they would go with that just to put the markers on the first defender.
Set.
On side nine, thank you.
It's a way to the right they come through.
Jordi Barrett and then a little set move on or cuddling up with Bowdoin.
Barrett still there for New Zealand though. Smith does well as he flirts with that sideline.
Jar stays in.
Eventually New Zealand rescue the ball back.
It's gone backwards a couple of times in there.
A little untidy from New Zealand.
Savia straight up the middle of one.
Good defence from Gawbisi.
Suwanga Fassi the next to carry forward.
Now from a standing start it's Dalton Papalei again.
And now New Zealand again trying to work a move in midfield.
No way through for Rico Ioanni the defence from Italy rock solid so far.
Hold that, hold that. Thank you.
Smith again looking for his runners and they all shimmy away to the left.
Brutalica had Cody Taylor with them.
And now they come back out open with Scott Barrett.
Just pressing and you heard the cry.
He's off his feet. They've got advantage here.
New Zealand for it's in there.
It's so difficult to put down in those close quarters.
New Zealand playing under advantage here.
Crossfield kick. Jordy Barrett into the arms of Will Jordan.
Jordan for the corner. Jordan with the flying finish.
Will Jordan's impeccable strike rate continues for New Zealand.
Well he's a man who can't finish.
He knows where the goal line is.
He knows how to get over.
The little kick over the top was just pinpoint accurate throwing dots.
And look at that for a dive.
Oh it's great execution.
That is a sensational kick pass.
And Jordan knew where the touch line was.
Knew he had to propel himself in the air.
And does it superbly.
That is absolutely brilliant.
There's no doubt that's a try.
The crowd don't like it.
Not sure why not.
Great score.
24th try in his 27th Test Match.
Will Jordan.
Coming back into the side today after one to forget against France.
He's put his team in the back row.
Richie Moong wants to convert from the side.
Slides this one inside the right hand upright at the good start.
Will Jordan and New Zealand.
Seven points to nil.
Beautiful kick there from Bodenbauer.
Look at that for a finish.
You don't get better than that Jordan with a fantastic dive.
One hand grounding.
Absolutely spot on.
I'm trying to understand why Stephen Varney was down in the corner.
And it wasn't Tomaso Allen.
Jordan Barrett brings down the restart.
New Zealand's 22.
It's a similar set up for New Zealand to work their way up.
If you're in front stay still.
Inside their own territory.
It's Bodenbauer who sends it up.
Coming forward for it.
It's just fell short of Tomaso Allen.
Bounce is kind though for Joani.
It was rounded upon by Shannon Frizzell back in the New Zealand side.
For the first time at this World Cup.
Italy look promising with their first early build up.
Again looking to punch some holes in this New Zealand line.
Through the impressive Lorenzo Canone and getting a penalty from it.
Assisted into the ground.
Never released.
Some really good options.
Some nice options used by the Italians.
A little pop pass into the hands of the big carrier.
Lorenzo Canone carried up strongly and then came the penalty.
Couple of nice little subtle offloads.
Little tip on passes.
Putting that New Zealand defence on a little bit of pressure.
Good response from the Italians.
Perfect, thank you.
He's 100% off the kicking to Tommy Allen.
Just be placing on our blind on the scrum okay.
Played a flop in the last game.
That is, it's got to be easy at 12.
It just gave them the attacking options.
I wouldn't have been surprised if it was thought out just to give them a little more practice in terms of who slots in where.
13 from 13 so far for Tommaso Allen.
This will take him second on Italy's all time point scoring list.
And he continues that perfect record.
Tommaso Allen with the penalty gets Italy on the board.
Responding to New Zealand's try.
First try, seven points to three.
Have to also remember that Italy's only less than 90 minutes away by car from the Italian border to get over to Lyon.
So they flooded this Lyon stage and they really have lots of Italian supporters.
Bowden Barrett with the restock on New Zealand and he's massively over cooked.
So mistake from the veteran All Black.
Will hand the scrum to Italy on halfway.
It's a game of such momentum isn't it.
Once you've conceded you really don't want to be making mistakes.
Once you've scored the last thing you want to do is give away points immediately.
The All Black scored, gave away three immediately and then made the little error with the overcooked kick.
This is a great little kick isn't it.
Jordy Barrett with just perfectly weighted kick pass.
Part of the new modern skill set of a rugby union player.
The ability to score in the corner while being tackled into touch.
Saw something similar here from Uruguay just two nights ago here in Lyon.
There went the Namibia.
Great attacking chance here though for Italy.
Scrum starts to wheel around and Vani scoots it away.
So when Ignacio Brex on the right just clatters forward the rock of the midfield for Italy.
Nice quick ball for them to work with here.
As the crowd groan at the heavy contact.
It's going to be a night of that.
No way through this time too for Rutzit as Frizzell man handles him.
Nice quick hands for Negri up over halfway.
Rutalik trying to get in there for New Zealand.
No it's still there for Italy.
Dino Lamb the next man forward and now Vani just rolls a little kick in behind.
Will Jordan and it's not going to be a 50-20 till it's taken back.
But it's still an excellent kick nonetheless.
It's an outstanding little kick that intentionally kicked it end over end with a little bit of topspin almost to get it running along the ground.
It scampered down into the corner.
Vani didn't play in the last game.
That is a super first little kick from him.
He's in it right now. It's been pretty good so far this Rugby World Cup.
They're going to have to be good on their goal line now.
Almost as if that kick Will Jordan tried to catch up with.
They didn't realise just what a good little roll on it had.
Now put him in the middle. Thank you. Perfect.
Short line out for New Zealand.
Taylor goes down to Scott Barrett at the back.
Nicely taken in.
Carried away by Hadi Saviour and the hard metres he so often makes.
Use it!
Smith will be the one to send this up for New Zealand.
It's going to come down for Monsi Ioani right on halfway.
A chance for Ioani to wind up back at the New Zealand line.
Gets through the first. Can't get past Frazelle but it's a good carry from the winger.
And now a little bit of what you can do.
I can't quite do better as it comes off the side and goes out on the full.
Just overcooked it slightly.
That is the man with the slippery little feet.
It's for you. Thank you.
Real handful, small, only 70 or so kilograms.
But boy he's got fast feet, gets around.
It's like a nail once he's going.
He's slippery, you can't get hold of him.
World Rugby breakthrough player of the year in 2022 Anj Kapowatso.
This time it's Ritellic for Cody Taylor who finds him.
And this is going to go down to Kapowatso on his own 22.
This is a regular player at fullback as well.
Here's Moorna.
And now Barrett looking for some open spaces.
Can't get this over the top of Garbisi though.
We thought we might see a little bit of this.
This kicking for territory, trying to manipulate and find some spaces.
Or Garbisi toward on the halfway line here.
Jordy Barrett was all over him.
I'm not sure the inside pass was quite expected there.
Did allow Jordy Barrett to get hands on the ball first.
Support maybe a fraction slow to clean out for Italy.
I'm not sure the inside pass was quite expected there.
Jordy Barrett's a tall fellow.
Cut himself off and bend down like that.
That's a great steal.
Here's that little inside pass.
Garbisi probably not the best man to carry it into contact.
And Barrett got hands on it.
Jordy Barrett a meter 96.
His brother Scott is 197.
The ball is away, flat and hard into the line.
It was Jordy Barrett.
It's awkward for Smith and they've got a penalty here in New Zealand.
Italian player.
Roll away.
New Zealand again will try a clever little kick through for Bowdoin Barrett to chase.
The bounce is good enough for Allen but they'll go back to the penalty.
Tackle her away please, into the path of the nine.
Giacomo Nicotero has just stayed down for a second.
I think he's the man who made that tackle on Jordy Barrett who came at real pace.
Gets a little hip slightly on the head there.
Down he goes.
Good line, good strong carry.
Good courage in the tackle.
Good courage in the carry as well.
Very interesting little kick over the top wasn't it?
Nice idea.
Switching from behind the right, behind the breakdown to the right.
Then kicking left again.
Found a bit of glass the kick so good idea.
Feels like with Jordy Barrett in there Shannon Frisell,
perhaps just that little extra physical edge in the New Zealand side tonight.
Jordy Barrett doing the kicking to the touchline.
We are accustomed to seeing the Chimuanga doing it.
Bowdoin Barrett does it.
Five, five.
Taylor again this time he finds Shannon Frisell.
New Zealand will set the drive on Frisell.
It's tucked under the left arm of Taylor.
The hook is six metres out.
Now a few others come to lens and wait.
Papaliti, Will Jordan is getting in there.
It's still there with Cody Taylor.
New Zealand got the momentum piling forward over the Italian line.
Try.
Superb set piece execution.
They're in Smithsnuck in there and stole the ball and got the try by the look of things.
All the backs were in. It was a real good push actually.
Try number 26 for the veteran Scrum Off.
Really well set up.
The ball at the back means it's hard to compete.
As soon as the march was on the backs came together.
It was a good start.
The back means it's hard to compete.
As soon as the march was on the backs came charging in.
There comes Will Jordan.
Aaron Smith just sneaks in the back there.
There he is. He's grabbed the ball.
He's gone, I'll have a piece of that and over he goes.
All clear.
Thank you, Brett.
When you've driven them around the park for 122 tests as a halfback,
you can probably sneak in and take it off the bat.
I guess he is the boss at that point.
He can't just come in and say, I'll have that one.
What I love about him is even though it's a mall try,
he just loves it as much as if he'd run 100 meters.
Similar position, slightly further in field for Richie Maung this time.
And again straight down the middle for New Zealand.
So a second converted try for the All Blacks and they lead Italy.
14 points to 3, 17 minutes gone in Lyon.
It's interesting because when you actually think about it,
Lyon was founded by the Romans of course,
but it's not the Italians who are getting scores here.
It's New Zealand just acting like Centurions going forward.
They're driving well, absolutely perfect.
Aaron Smith and not Cody Taylor finishing it off.
Fantastic score, great teamwork.
There's been an early change here for Italy.
Daniele Fischietti, the loose-haired props being replaced by Ivan Nemer.
Here's Savia clattering through the line into open spaces for New Zealand.
Got support on the inside and outside.
Barrett is there, he had Taylor looming up, Barrett spins out of one.
For Lea with open territory, Mark de Lea.
Step, step through the line, crashes over.
New Zealand break out from the restart in their own 22
and the finish from Mark de Lea.
Well, the danger of the All Blacks, laying down a marker.
Oh, Savia, just such a perfectly timed line, the angle good.
Straight through he went, options left and right.
Look for Barrett, he maybe came inside a bit soon,
but had the presence of mind to throw it wide to Taylor.
Thought he was going to just put the gas down and hit for the corner.
Had a bit of work to do and did it brilliantly.
Super finish, great team try, great counter attack try from the kickoff from deep.
Oh, he is electric.
Well, you don't often see them that animated this early in a match.
And Italy, who desperately needed to start so well,
have been rocked back by a third New Zealand try.
And I know we hate talking about statistics,
but Italy's average score against the All Blacks at Rugby World Cup
is a loss of just a smudge under 60 points.
Richie Munger just shaves it inside for Hitu.
Perfect so far.
New Zealand going up in multiples of seven.
Nearly 21 points to three.
Almost 20 minutes gone.
This is Daniel Fiskeate.
Yeah, he's not in a great place just holding that left chest, of course.
It's a pack injury really being taken off,
and he's not in a good place.
We'll get an update with that injury a bit later on.
Use it!
Smith sends it up towards the halfway line.
Alan underneath this one and takes it really well.
Here's the oncoming All Blacks defence just rounds upon Negri.
And look at Papalei, he barred all, barrelling over.
Smith, yeah, lost it on the ground.
He said it was a fair competition.
Good counter-ruck from Italy in the end.
Landstuck holding onto this one though.
And it was Cody Taylor who had all rights to it.
Great little Jackal.
Got his hands on the ball.
First there, first hands on.
Immovable once he was set.
Low centre of gravity.
He does bring that Jackal ability to the side, doesn't he?
And having scored three tries already, no surprise.
The All Blacks quite happy to go to the touchline now.
It's interesting hearing from Ian Foster just before the clash.
When you talk about the speed of getting down into the rucks and being very quick.
The Italians are number one at this Rugby World Cup.
But on that occasion, who was number one?
Well, no one else but, of course, the All Blacks.
Going straight in there and retrieving the ball, getting possession back.
Three turnovers won from the All Blacks.
Over 15.
It's Taylor again.
It's down the back for Purzell.
Quick for Savia.
Adi Savia.
You're never stopping him from there.
Well, it's wonderful defending.
It's got to be sad.
Great run from Adi Savia.
But Italy have missed seven tackles in the build-up to this try.
So, yes, it's gone through.
Almost untouched.
No tackle really attempted.
No heart, no commitment in the defensive effort.
And that Italy is not one they'll want to see.
Look at this round the corner, a little step inside.
All too easy.
Captain extraordinaire.
Almost untouched.
And that about sums up the defensive effort, really.
It was very similar for the last try as well, Joel, with Mark Talia.
I counted five missed tackles.
And it can't be going down well with this man, Kieran Crowley, of course,
who really wanted a first 20 minutes to go.
High pressure, high tempo rugby against the All Blacks.
Just to give them a little bit of a rattle.
Hasn't been the case.
They're just not able to defend properly at the moment.
Moreman converts again.
New Zealand streaking away in the first half.
Try for the captain, Adi Savia.
28 points to three.
Yeah, just too soft.
There's one attempt to tackle.
It's a poor one.
And two robbies.
Point.
It's eight missed tackles now.
Too soft for the...
He is a great runner.
He's picked some really good lines.
And it was another good line, but that is soft defensive effort.
Oh, Italy kick off again.
And that's a good one.
Need to regroup and regroup quickly as Delia steps out of the first tackle.
Can't get through the oncoming Italian defense.
An Italian defense that is the first for tackle success.
They've been so good throughout the tournament.
Not so far tonight as New Zealand exit out of their own 22.
All a little sedate there for a second.
Probably in the greatest scheme not a bad exit.
Tasmin Italy will have a little chance here inside the old black territory to maybe go through the phases.
They were pretty good ball in hand in the first five minutes or so.
That one not straight.
So one of Italy's top players, Adi Savia, is going to be a bit of a tough one.
Not straight.
So one of Italy's features of the tournament so far also falling apart on them.
Pressure. It's about pressure.
I think they've lost a little bit of their composure.
You know, you obviously when you can see two quick tries in succession like that, obviously your heads are dropping.
And he's trying to understand what's going on.
You've really got to just remain focused and still get in.
The pressure's always on you.
You know, it's a Rugby World Cup game, of course, against one of the best teams in the world.
You can't drop your heads.
Particularly, Robbie, when you have high expectations and high hopes.
Behind.
Set.
Stay up.
There's a good scrum for New Zealand.
They've got a penalty here as well.
And Savia peels off once more.
Jordan, a little chip kick over the top for himself.
Italy's defence will come across and they'll go back to the scrum penalty against Riccioni.
Well, the set-phase proving a little traumatic here for the clear line-out goes awry.
The scrum penalty against them.
They've had that early change in the front row already with Danilo Fiscati becoming injured.
Even Nema is on the field and skew one-out throw.
Robbie spoke about the dropping heads, the skew throw and the penalty at scrum won't help matters at all.
That's a great kick to the touchline.
Well, it's legends row, isn't it?
Richie McCaw in the middle, Stephen Donald Conrad, Smith All Blacks World Cup winners.
Louis Pecumault, one of the greats of French rugby.
I think those three in the middle are quite happy with what they've seen.
I think they'll be delighted right now.
Another great attacking chance for New Zealand.
They've gone down the back towards Brazil in these previously.
This time it's Retalic near the front.
And they have another more and it's there with Cody Taylor.
And then Smith comes up to bar quarters.
And it's forward pack.
They've got all the momentum again and can Taylor with the control in the back.
It's still moving forward.
Now Taylor peels away.
Smith steps, Stephen is over again.
Aaron Smith gets the second.
Well, this time around you can thank Cody Taylor.
The mall was just edging forward enough to hold all the Italian forwards inside that mall.
Keep them busy, keep them pushing.
Peel to the right, the quick hands and Smith with a one on one.
That close, so hard to stop.
No contest at the line out.
Real determination and hardware getting the mall just edging forward,
just sucking in those Italian defenders, all the forwards involved.
And then Cody Taylor just realizes there's a bit of space on the right.
It's coming to a little bit of a standstill.
And Smith, he's just so nippy.
Over he goes.
Richie Moonga from a similar position where he's hit two.
And this time again what they can do, barely a thing wrong at the moment, New Zealand.
Just look at this, look at the structure of this driving mall, you know,
before Cody gets the, Cody Taylor gets the ball out into the hands of Aaron Smith.
It's just so well structured.
When the ball's taken, snatched out of the air by Brodie Rettellick,
they really do have a very well organized protected unit with the ball at the back.
You can move forward.
There's communication from your number nine as well.
It's absolutely perfectly executed.
The live letter as we see it at the moment.
If it stays this way for New Zealand.
Taken in.
New Zealand still have Uruguay to play.
Italy will take on France next week.
Back to back games here in Lyon.
Smith puts this up for Talia to chase but Tommaso Alen will come forward
and then gets hammered by Mark Talia.
It's fallen awkwardly and then eventually scooted up by Garbisi.
So crisis averted and now some numbers and some space for one.
Ignacio Brax, Oslo, Fulcanoni hits the chest and away they go.
And New Zealand playing under advantage.
Broken play is dangerous.
Brazell straight up through the middle, just plowing his way forward.
Shannon Brazell able to go again.
And New Zealand just quickly swing from defense to attack.
Bodenbarrett to the 22.
Off your feet.
Here's Frazell again who made that big charge.
Just bumps off another one.
The physical presence of Shannon Frazell.
Moonga to Scott Barrett.
Now Rico Ioane and just lost it.
Somewhere on the ground New Zealand.
But they are just bending and pressing and pressurizing Italy at every turn.
I think that's their first mistake tonight, isn't it?
30 minutes in, the first error they've made.
Being really polished, really accurate, determined.
Said before the game it would be a bit of a test of wills for both teams.
New Zealand looking to bounce back.
Izzy looking to hang in there against a real contender.
The All Blacks have laid down the marker you spoke about Ricky.
They have certainly shown a clinical execution side.
And a desire to keep on searching for that goal line over and over again.
Half an hour gone, New Zealand five tries.
All converted by Ricci Moonga.
55 points to three, they lead Italy.
Set.
Just coming back to Ricci Moonga, he's kicked them from everywhere hasn't he?
He's had three from the right-hand corner.
One Izzy, one from the left.
It doesn't look like missing.
There was only one from three in that opening game against France.
And he didn't play against Namibia or didn't kick against Namibia when he came on.
Took a little knock at training a couple of days ago too.
But doesn't seem to have any issues.
He's got to have equal pressure.
Let's get higher on this side please.
Well he's moving smoothly, he's controlling things beautifully, he's kicking.
It's just like a dart, he's just nailing them from everywhere.
50 second captain out for Ricci Moonga.
Behind.
Set.
Penalty or free kick rather, New Zealand.
He's stepping away, stay over the mark.
Italy just not taking that wake, stepping back at New Zealand.
Sniffing blood here in the Italian scrum.
Stay up, stay over the mark.
He's got to be on the line.
Picture tells a story sometimes, disappointment on the face of the Italian front row.
He'll be under a little more pressure now than New Zealand put in.
Tacking options both sides.
They come away to the left with Ricci Moonga, cut out ball for Ioanni.
He's got to Leo but he's also got plenty of pace.
Good tackle though by Brix around the ankles.
Salvia for Scott Barrett.
Again New Zealand just asking questions of the Italian defence
and for the first time it breaks down on attack.
We'll get a lead off this time, Italy.
It's hoofed downfield to Will Jordan on his own 10 metre line.
Jordan sizing up the options, looking for that little half gap that he needs,
that he almost found as well.
Good tackle, Ruzza.
Scott Barrett again out the back four, Moonga and then the hole for Jordi Barrett.
He's got Aaron Smith up the middle and Aaron Smith's going to get a hat-trick.
And the easiest one so far.
Jumped in the mall to get his first.
Had a lot of work to do around the mall for his second.
He's got a simple little run in here.
Will Jordan, boy, he just looked around such in defenders,
gave them go forward and then Bowdoin Barrett ran such a good line.
An easy counter-end for Aaron Smith.
Richie Moonga made the spot there, realised there was a little bit of space in behind,
he could get in behind the shoulders of one defender.
Freed up Bowdoin Barrett, he freed up this man,
hat-trick for the little veteran scrum-off.
Nice little thank you really and acknowledgement of the work of Bowdoin Barrett.
42 points to three, 55 minutes gone.
It is a black wave that has hit Italy in this first half.
Richie Moonga, what he actually does is, you know, he just holds it back for just that extra half second.
That sucks in the defenders and just enables them to commit themselves
and then he makes the pass, it's just absolutely beautiful to watch.
Another restart for Italy, Rico Imani this time.
New Zealand just full of running.
Tackle, let him go!
Big body flanker goes to ground and another penalty.
Tackle, no release, then fell to the wrong side.
New Zealand have just been able to set the tempo, play at the pace they want to,
that the likes of France didn't let them do.
And they do look to speed it up, don't they?
They're not able this time because the tackle man not released in the tackle.
Well before the game started we thought New Zealand would win it,
we thought they would maybe run away in the second half,
but not resoundingly so like this in the first half.
Thank you.
Six tries already, more than a point a minute.
Cody Taylor for Frizzell, Papalei.
And now flat for Jordi Barrett, little flip ball out the back of the hand for Jordan.
And again New Zealand just pour forward, they slip off tackles once more.
To Italy, Asavio goes up over the 22, followed up by Rutellic,
the ball is quick for New Zealand.
Barrett to Barrett, the hands this time just slipped down
and it will come undone until he's shooting up to put the ball in.
And then it's a good time to go for the ball.
This time just slipped down and it will come undone until he's shooting up to put some pressure on.
Italian player, then backwards, so knock on first, Scrum White.
Well the Italian defence is looking ragged, even when they're getting up and making tackles.
They're getting forced backwards, they're not winning the confrontation on the tackle line, on the gain line.
Just at the end there they got up and forced the error,
but they were already way back behind where play started.
And then they come off.
I look on my shell shock, they should be.
The one thing that they're having problems with is just ball retention, not getting possession.
If you don't get possession you can't really, you're just going to be chasing shadows all night.
We know how deadly the All Blacks are when they've got the ball in hand
and they're passing it around, they just look as though they're, you know, it's poetry in motion.
So the moment that the Italians don't have the ball in hand, they can't really do anything with it.
They're just going to just take the hits and if their defence is not up to scratch in the missing tackles,
then you know, the floodgates are going to open up.
That's what's happened so far.
It doesn't help when you play most of the game and you're only 22 as well, Robbie.
The New Zealand kicking game, the carry game, it's just forced Italy back.
408 metres made already by the All Blacks.
And just 51 carries.
Five line breaks.
We thought there would be more kicking as well from, you know, the likes of Gabiisi and the likes of Tomaso Allen.
They've got great kicking, you know, kicking game, you know, play the territory game, get it out of your own heart.
They haven't even been able to really do that because, well, the possession, they just haven't had the possession.
Only 31% possession, so absolutely nothing.
And I guess when you've got such a little ball you don't want to group it away
and give the opposition another opportunity to counter-attack every time.
New Zealand also very quick on the, you know, in the rucks.
So even if you do have an isolated break, you know, you need support players right behind the cavalry.
They need to be there.
If they're not there, then you'll see the Italian, you know, the Black Mire that will just, you know,
envelop and seize possession again.
Problems in the prime row for Italy.
Giacomo Nicotetto, he's got a little bit of a lead there.
Giacomo Nicotetto, a little bang on the head early on.
Biscuit has been replaced already.
And Cironi is in the wars now.
Here we are, guys, here we are.
Let's focus, let's focus.
New Zealand have won a scrum penalty, they've had a free kick as well.
Let's see if their front row can exert some pressure here.
And the Italian, they've got a good hit.
But this is a slightly early for New Zealand free kick for Italy.
Little mini victory for Italy, for the front row in particular.
Boost their confidence a little bit, just on the brink of half-time.
And look to Delia, I don't know if this is found touch from Garbisi,
it's not found close to touch.
So Mark Delia and Bode and Barrett get a chance to have a look at the options,
and Barrett sends it back down with interest.
He does find the sideline.
And no chance for Italy to go quickly at all.
Well, Garbisi won't be too unhappy with that.
It was a free kick, couldn't kick it out on the fore and retain the line out.
So actually they've made 30 metres and got the opportunity to throw the ball in the line-up.
And a chance just to keep the ball a little bit.
Go through the phases, build some momentum.
They're being urged on now by the crowd, this partisan Italian crowd.
Good take from Ferreri Coruzza.
Body's in motion for it, they're trying to get Caporso into it instead.
It goes for Bratz now.
A little bit of space for Montewani, gets some footwork on Will Jordan,
who comes across and makes the tackle.
Some good front foot ball for the Italians to work with here,
but no way through for Lannes.
He is just a roughhouse to the ground by Rutalic.
And then it's lost, Saviour.
Uwane for Will Jordan.
And Van de Joven, a little chip-kick for himself almost.
There on the bounce, Vani got back in time.
But huge pressure on Uwane.
All Black's coming in.
Italians get back in numbers just in time.
And now Peg back on their own five metre line.
Penalty, Italy.
Montewani did unbelievably well there.
Tackle, two all Blacks all over him.
Managed to put the ball down, get on his feet.
Stay over it.
And by time for his teammates to get there.
Brilliant work.
I think he defied gravity there, didn't he Joel?
It was pretty impressive.
He just managed to just hold it, waited for his teammates to get back.
And then, yeah, they win the penalty.
Pretty impressive stuff that was.
And just when you thought that they were on for another try to extend that advantage.
Yeah, a nice little moment as well.
It's just past time to get to half time.
The Italians will put the ball in, they'll go through the phases.
Try and come away unscathed on the brink of the break.
Again, it's good from Rutalic for Vani.
And now through the hands they go.
The captain, Michele Lamaro.
Shoveled on by Garbisi for Brits.
And now Ioanni coming off his wing to find Kapuotsu.
Who's scragged and rolled and awkward.
And the penalty comes for New Zealand.
Just too good at the breakdown.
That's what happens when you go tip to tip.
Sometimes you run out of forwards to give you the real oomph you need out wide there.
Particularly when you've got a little man.
He's a great handful.
He's a proper runner, ball and hand.
But he's only 70 kilograms.
Kapuotsu.
The All Blacks just too good at the breakdown this time.
And Italy are going to have to defend inside their 22 again.
We tick over the 40-minute mark at New Zealand.
Already six tries in this opening half.
Taylor again finds Frazel.
Line out his work to perfection.
Jordi Baric tries to roll over the top of Lamaro.
Can't do so.
But they pile forward.
De Lerre in close where he's so difficult to stop.
Smith for Mfasi for Retalek.
And another advantage for New Zealand as well as the pressure comes on.
Nipolalala has stopped in his track.
But New Zealand still playing with the advantage.
Pick and go from Cody Taylor.
In fact he shovels it on for Tohono Fasi.
Taylor again this time does try and go at the middle.
And then they get him behind and almost shovel their way through.
It's there for Aaron Smith.
Moonga.
Again Moonga just puts it down this time.
They were still playing under the penalty advantage though.
So the pressure not over walls, Smith.
Number eight was your offside.
Option New Zealand.
You were fine but the tackler must move before you can have a jackal.
Took a little while to make the decision there didn't it.
Look for all money that Aaron Smith is going to tap and go and play quickly.
Eventually it's going to be the mall I would think.
And then they're going to have to go for the ball.
Uh oh Mala.
Tohono Fasi goes into this time crisis,
but they look fantastic Will,
I'm sure their offside that Aaron
Smith was going to tap and go and play quickly.
Eventually it's going to be the mall, I would think.
Stuck under one.
And this time it's a leak.
Gonna have to let it come.
Another advantage for New Zealand.
So Frazell with a little shuffle, the off-load.
For Tuunga Fasi again, or for Tuunga Fasi four meters out.
Frazell's the next man to line up.
Just tirelessly working into that Italian line.
They must have numbers out there somewhere, the All Blacks.
A little chip kick over the top is deep in the effort
from Taylor.
Would have been spectacular.
They were still playing with the penalty though.
Number eight.
You must be supporting your body weight.
Would have been spectacular.
This has been gathered.
Look at the dive and the commitment.
Oh, Cody Taylor.
Oh, specky dive.
Not sure he was ever gonna get there.
Had a full go though.
If I told you Fasi's been pretty strong with ball carry,
hasn't he?
Balling out, he's been one of the pillars
around the fringes.
By that I mean one of the real strong ball carriers,
not defenders.
Oh, that's a high four.
Would have been one of the great hooker tries though.
He's been busy.
Cody Taylor and executed when it's mattered
as Ian Foster happily head for the changing rooms.
Frazelle.
New Zealand again will get this drive rolling.
It's Elise splintering and scattering,
piling in the black shirt.
Still there for New Zealand.
Closer.
And they're just getting started.
Oh, that's a good one.
Still there for New Zealand.
Close to the line.
It's almost stopped now.
It'll have to come out.
It's got there for Adi Savia.
Trying to sneak around the corner.
Another advantage and another try for Adi Savia.
Just so clinic already.
All the options at the line out.
Dummy mall, the line out before this time.
Well set up, well structured, well defended as well,
to be fair to Italy.
And then eventually,
Savia just realized there was no one on that left hand side,
no one to defend the little peel.
Peel he did.
No one there to stop him.
Look at this rumbling forward.
All of a sudden it came to a halt.
The ball's so well controlled at the back.
Now, Savia looks up,
sees that there's a better space.
No one's going to stop him that close.
It's so much about the intelligence of knowing when to go,
knowing until the right time to actually peel off
and then dive over.
They just know it.
It's in their DNA, isn't it?
Brilliant, brilliant score.
But again, you can look at the team effort
in that driving mall.
Black's captain Sam Kane.
We're going to see his first appearance at this World Cup
sometime in the second half.
Richie Moonga to cap a near perfect 45 minutes
of rapid for the All Blacks.
Bowden Barrett to start the second half for New Zealand
leading Italy, 59 points to three.
As Lorenzo Canone takes it up,
couple of sets of brothers out there for either side.
And an early penalty goes against New Zealand.
Steven Varney milked it nicely though, didn't he?
Made it nice and obvious, won the penalty,
won the free clearance.
Jordi Barrett, just not rolling east to west,
just trying to almost get the ball in the net.
just trying to almost get in the way.
One never knows whether it's intentional or not,
but certainly penalized.
Nicoletti Da'Oro, Italian, contesting this one,
but it lands nicely for Italy this time.
Here's one Ignacio Breck on the wraparound.
And now a little bit of running from Italy.
Ioanni was the dummy runner, Capozzo,
just no room for him and no way through Tellea.
Needed to be a bit courageous in chance,
their army here's Breck's again,
and that's a nice direct run from the center up the middle.
Much better start from Italy in this half.
Peeling off some meters this time, Seb Negri.
Tonefasi eventually gets to his feet, up over halfway.
Build some momentum and confidence
as the Tellea chant rings around,
and that's a nice stepping, jinking, weaving run.
Here's Allen, close to the sideline,
bundled out over the sideline, it comes undone for Italy.
He's still alive.
It's a great pull-up though, isn't it?
It's just what the Italians needed to do,
just what the crowd wanted.
Corbisi did so well to get around the corner,
the little show and go.
Allen was looking for someone on his outside there,
but I think it was Lamarro,
he'd just run the inside line,
and Tommy Allen bundled into touch.
Line out one by Brodie Ritellic again for New Zealand,
it's sent down more than two.
Kapuotso, Kapuotso, maybe a chance
to get those flying feet going,
chants the arm with that elusive,
jinking running style he has.
Can't go through Jordi Barrett.
Slowly, that's fine.
Penalty advantage for Black offside.
And they've drawn another penalty here,
Ritellic caught offside for New Zealanders.
Piccioni bobbles that one.
Advantage wide.
Still advantage for Italy here.
These bricks again,
has had two or three really good carries
in these opening couple of minutes.
Oh, real trouble.
Still advancing, Stephen.
But Piccioni, that play's gonna make his way
to this breakdown.
Here's Nicola Canone up over the 22,
New Zealand going to steal this one away,
and gonna, yes, go back to play the penalty
for Ritellic offside.
Well, it's a gutsy start to the second half from Italy.
Courageous, gutsy.
Kieran Crowley will be really happy with the way
they've come out and played with real art
in this first three or four minutes.
Looked after the ball.
He spoke about the All Blacks being happy
about not conceding penalties well.
Two very quick defensive penalties gone.
Oh, he took a bump, didn't he?
Marco Riccioni did well to get up
and get to the next two breakdowns, actually.
It's actually nice to see Italy
with a little bit more possession in their hands, you know?
That was a good number of phases
when they were just passing the ball around,
keeping it tight, going into the tackle,
but also seeing support players arrive really quickly,
and that enabled them to draw the penalty.
And of course, they've got a good attacking platform here
to try and get themselves their first try at this game.
A rare foray into the New Zealand 22.
Nicoltera needs to find his mark,
but it's Ritellic who gets up for New Zealand.
Celia there to carry forward for the All Blacks.
They try and rip it off them.
And they get a penalty too in New Zealand.
Moment lost for Italy.
A lot of movement in that line out,
and ultimately Brodie Ritellic just got up there
with his big mitts and stole the ball.
Is that out?
No.
Barrett doesn't find touch.
You can see New Zealand wanting to play quickly,
but Barney did well to get back there.
He's driven this down straight to Bowdoin.
Barrett though on the 22.
And now he's got more on it,
and there could be danger.
Jordan just tipped up by Brex.
Hekuani outside, and Italy have done well to,
ooh, just stole up the ball and earned the penalty.
Good fight back from Italy.
Three penalties on the truck going against the All Blacks.
Not quite in on the truck,
but three they will not be particularly happy with.
Good contest on the ground.
And that's a great touch, Rhonda.
I'm glad you got to the point.
Brodie, you said it at the break.
Italy haven't scored against the All Blacks since 2016.
Timing with the movement.
Tommaso Boni was that man.
Timing, movement before the ball.
Make sure we don't move before the ball is thrown.
Gotta get the line out right firstly, that.
Oh, no.
New Zealand contestants landed in the hands
of Shannon Frizzell.
Just plucked it away with ease.
New Zealand will get to exit through Richie Mo'unga again.
13, 13, 13!
Okay, legs up.
Oh, it's another line out that's just not gone
according to plan.
No one's gone up, and it's just.
Too easy for Shannon Frizzell.
It's almost like he knew where the ball was gonna come.
The contest with the pot went up.
Didn't even get as far as the Italian captain, Romaro.
Time's up.
Well, Marco Riccioni's going to have
a head injury assessment after that knock he took earlier.
That brings Simone Ferrari on in jersey 18.
Beep.
Plucked away this time from Ruzza.
Advantage.
And they've got another penalty here at least.
So New Zealand's starting to concede a couple of penalties
early in this half.
Vani again, there's the new man, Ferrari.
Races into the line.
Negri. Still playing.
Vani had to flick it away.
It was awkward, and oh, Lala grabs the loose ball
but they were playing a penalty.
Well, the rock speed for Italy is really quick at the moment.
That ball coming up nice and quickly.
Well presented.
Number five jumping across.
The clean out is good.
The ball presented very quickly indeed.
That's just too quickly.
Brilliant kick again, but so close to being dead.
Gotta win the line out now.
Italian fans urging their team on.
All the pressure on Giacomo Nicotera.
He goes to the front for Canone.
And Italy will be roared on here.
New Zealand have got really well organised though
straight away and have held this drive up.
In fact, Italy have lost ground.
So Vani has to use it for bricks.
Through the hands they go.
Ioani on Ioani and it's Monty who wins out here.
Capuazzo.
Capuazzo for the corner.
Capuazzo for the try.
It finally comes and it's the magic feat of Ange Capuazzo.
Well, what a moment for the young winger.
Real pace, had a lot of work to do.
Showed some pace.
This ball finally won at the line out.
It couldn't be mauled.
It came out the back.
The organisation, the lines were good.
Ioani did brilliantly to draw two defenders.
Capuazzo had loads of pace to get in at the corner.
He had a lot to do the young winger, didn't he?
He did well.
There's a lot of work to do.
The young winger, didn't he?
He did well.
Ioani drew two defenders.
Alan's hands were good.
Loads to do.
Brilliant from the young winger.
And loads to shout about for the crowd.
He needs to take a bow.
He made that.
Quality finish from a quality player.
And I'll put it back on.
Tries all clear as well.
Shot clock is back on.
Tommie Allen remains perfect.
49 points to 10.
But after making his debut as a 21 year old,
some 13 years ago,
a two time World Cup winner playing his fourth World Cup,
Samuel Whitelock,
surpasses the great Richie McCaw
as the most cat door black of all time.
His world record is now at the top of the table.
He's got a lot of work to do.
This time, his 149th appearance for New Zealand.
Hang on, hang on.
What a moment for the big second row.
The great servants of New Zealand rugby
and wonderful to get their paws down
on the record breaking cap.
Hettling choosing to play from deep once again.
Pretty good when they've had a go.
Charge down from New Zealand and Scott Barrett's
gonna get down low to scoop this up.
Whitelock there in support.
Here they come, Terrell Lomax onto the field as well
for the Kiwis.
Tam Roygaard there and Brodie Retellix over the line.
I spoke too soon.
For the first time, Hettling inside there 22
in the second off, choosing to kick the kick.
Charge down.
And the big second row, Brodie Retellix is in.
His ninth test match try.
And over 50 goes the scoreboard.
Yeah, it's the substitute number nine, of course,
Martin Pajrello, the former Toulousean.
Great charge down, isn't it?
Just makes it really complicated with the scrambling defense.
And then afterwards, you know, it's just from close range
and you won't stop that man there,
Brodie Retellix, from scoring from that distance, of course.
But not a great start for the number nine
who's just come off the bench to replace Stephen Varney.
Good little pick up as well from Scott Barrett, actually.
Had that incident there.
Ball hopping around awkwardly, picked it up comfortably,
made the charge.
And then the second carry from Retellix.
Please, nothing silly now,
which is gonna make me wanna escalate.
Thank you.
New Zealand strikes straight back after conceding that try
as they tick over 50.
Well, the goal kicking has just been superb
from both Moana and Tomaso Allen today.
Here's another for Jett Moana to make it 56 points to 10.
Is that the same for that?
Thank you.
The score is now 16 to 11.
New Zealand, the world's second-best team,
they have won this before.
Stack of changes for New Zealand in that period, too.
It's a mighty Williams out there
for his first Rugby World Cup appearance,
Torell Lomax, Cam Roygaard.
Wait!
Okay, fall out.
Good exit in the end.
Is Italy having just got a little bit behind
and they can see points straight away.
Yeah, they made such a good start to the second half
and got the first try in seven years against the All Blacks.
And then the little error, the charge-down kick
and they're back under pressure.
Over 15.
Barrett.
New Zealand have got Whitelock, Barrett and Britalical out there.
Shannon Frazell was the man who went to the bench.
Roygaard out there for Aaron Smith.
Thank you, 20.
Backwards, there.
That one's through the hands.
Obviously, they can try and put some pressure on here,
but Jordan recovers well for Roygaard.
Now Moana's gonna send this for Tellia to chase
and the bounces, well, is kind in the end for Capuazzo
and this is where he's really dangerous.
Can't get past Rico Ioanni though.
And then it's Messi untidy, Roygaard scooped it up.
Ioanni with a little bit of not much room to move at all,
in fact.
Big shot comes on, a scrappy barrier to play,
but it's gonna get loose and it could get open.
Very loose.
Little bit.
On the verge of messy there,
you can understand what was happening,
the little attempted grubber through,
the little chip over the top as it got a little untidy.
And then it's gone.
Also got a change in the front row for Italy
with Heemi Fiber coming on to replace Giacomo Nicotera.
There's also a significant change in the all-black pack
that needs to be mentioned.
Scott Barrett has moved to the flank position.
Both teams meet me over the mark,
so we need equal pressure.
Shannon Frazell after a really industrious 40 minutes.
Welcome back to him, but Barrett is now
on the side of the scrum.
And at some point they would do this
because in the big games against the big heavy teams,
it's where New Zealand would like to employ the services.
It means they've got a bit more weight,
bit more strength in that loose forward trail.
That scrum just powering forward from New Zealand,
massive front football for Barrett to his brother, Bodin.
And now room on the outside,
back in field for Bodin, Barrett from Jordan.
Jordan scoots it up in the blink of an eye,
New Zealand attack again.
Ioani will clear for Jordi Barrett,
taking it up hard himself.
The youngest of the three brothers out there.
Through the hands, Mo'unga, now Barrett
with the cross-field kick for Telia.
Oh, Kapuotsu did well.
And now he's gonna take off on Kapuotsu.
Went for the little kick, got taken just in time.
It's gonna open up here for Kam Royga to step inside.
Roll and almost score.
Well, it's all over the place.
They're going to have to check
whether Royga rolled or got there.
We've got an on-field decision of a try.
So just wanna check how the player got over the goal line.
Well, it's a great tackle back by Mo'aselea.
On-field decision is a try.
We'd just like to check whether there's momentum
or whether he compels himself to get to the goal line.
And we just check whether the rolling extra movement
gets him over the line or whether there's momentum does.
Kam Royga almost gave himself up a little bit here.
Here comes your first camera angle, Matt.
We are not going to pass it over.
Does he get that extra roll?
I think there's another little movement there.
We've got full speed to determine the momentum, please, Brad.
I could get stuck a little bit in two minds,
do I or don't I?
He's not placed it down and then he just,
oh, I'll just have another little shift of the ball.
Italian fans know what they think has happened.
We're just gonna come back to the main camera angle
and play that at live speed for you.
Thank you.
I think he rolls himself forward.
And the ball is short
and then he shuffles it to the line anyway.
So it's gonna be no try.
You happy with that, Vez?
Yeah.
Brad?
Coming back to you now, Matthew.
Okay, so we believe that the player
has taken an extra movement,
an extra roll to propel himself,
so it will be no try.
No worries, you're on screen now.
No try.
Well, I think that's the right decision,
Brett Cronin and Matthew Cardy have made the right call.
You said it, he seemed to stop and then he went,
just, I just shifted a little under the line.
And I like the fact that advantage is called over
because he seemed to certainly could have,
should have scored.
You know, I think that Kam Roycard was actually,
he wanted to set it up, you know,
set up the next platform so that someone came in
and took the ball from the rack
because he didn't realize how close he was to the line,
I think, you know?
Otherwise, he could have actually gone for it.
Maybe it would have been a try, but in any case, not given.
Here we go, thank you.
Great decision.
Hami Faiver.
He's overthrown that one.
Cody Taylor's just gonna swoop on it.
Here's Delia, really dangerous and broken play like this.
The hands are outstanding from Papaliti.
And New Zealand again punished the errors
from Italy, Dolsan Papaliti this time.
Well, it's another line-up that's gone awry.
And New Zealand punishing.
Thank you, Brett.
An inaccurate Italian line-up.
It's a poor effort really over the back two,
a free ball and Delia just was onto it
in a flash through he went, almost got away himself.
It's a great little pick-up here from Papaliti.
No one's gonna stop him from that close.
Well, they've been their own worst enemy today, Italy.
A number of errors, number of mistakes,
particularly around the line-up.
Richie Moana adds the two, 100% for Richie tonight.
They've got to get the line-outs right.
Even though they saw that, well,
they were just overthrown there by Hami Faiver.
And then afterwards, well,
we just know exactly what they do.
Collect it, pass it, storm through.
The juggernauts arrive and more points scored.
There's scrambling Italian defence
unable to defend properly.
63 points to 10 now.
Still 24 or so minutes to play in this match.
New Zealand with nine tries.
And Will Jordan not happy with that clearance
and you're rightly so.
Two and seven replacing two and seven.
Two players coming on as you can see.
Team captain Sam Kane.
Dane Coles, Cody Taylor making way for him.
And then of course you can see it's that man
who just scored the try, Dalton Papalai.
Just a quick 180 caps coming onto the field
here between two players.
Sam Kane and Dane Coles collectively there.
189 and 179.
And then they get the gap for the two.
New Zealand again can test the line out
and again they've got more ball.
And now Willing and Ready to run from Deep Delia.
Steps through one and then look to force the ball
in traffic, it's gone forward out of the hands from them.
Let off for Italy.
They've shown they can open them up.
New Zealand's defence still rock solid.
Sam might like that one.
Backwards under pressure.
We'll come back for the knock on.
Going to go back and play the original knock on here
from New Zealand though.
Or forward pass, sorry.
Well about a go haven't they, Italy.
They've gone backwards, gone back for the advantage.
Good refereeing.
Cloud trying to get in behind that team.
Just make sure we meet with equal force.
First scrim for the New Zealand front row
which has the 23 year old to Mighty Williams
all 139, 40 odd kilos of him.
I think he may have slimmed down a little actually
now that I see him on that side of the scrim.
Terrell Lomax on the other side.
His first appearance, that heavy bandage on the knee.
30 stitches in that knee after the loss at Twickenham.
Oh, it was a nasty gash that wasn't it.
It was a nasty gash.
A nasty gash that wasn't it.
Crouch.
Bind.
Set.
Hold.
There was an area of the game at Twickenham
where he almost battled against the Springlocks
in the front row.
Let's go again, let's go.
Come on.
He's been vastly improved over the last few weeks.
Let's go.
Control.
A real handful, a powerful ball carrier.
Low centre of gravity.
Getting ready to make his way on.
It's the crowd booing each other.
The wave stopping somewhere.
Now it's got some momentum.
We'll see if Italy can get some too.
Go, Italy!
It's in Paj.
It's a scrum penalty, New Zealand.
Always backpedalling.
We're the Italians.
Let's go and see.
It's the change with Paolo Adogu coming on to replace
Tomas Atalani.
Just hold him, Christoph.
It's about the same, Robbie.
It's particularly from on the field down there.
The kicking out of hand, the kicking for goal is at 100%,
but the kicking out of hand and touch at the corners
has also been just superb tonight.
And Kappu Ozo is going to move to full back, obviously.
Adogu on the wing.
Completed.
Tomas Ozo's record stays perfect.
He's become Italy's second all-time leading points scorer
and become their highest points scorer.
And Robbie Willard cuts as New Zealand peel away again.
Kane for Coles in the corner.
Set-move perfection once more.
They bamboozled the Italian defense
and the old stage-a-day Coles gets a try.
I think they're laughing because it's his first touch.
Dade Coles, the wars, the old veteran,
89th cap tonight.
Keep talking about the caps,
this is a highly experienced all-black side experience
coming to the fore, the execution just perfect.
You knew where the space was.
Taking the line out good.
Round the corner they came.
Kane to Coles.
The combination, perfect.
They're all smiling.
10th try of the night, good reason to smile.
The only man not smiling is Richie Ngwange.
He's going, you put it in the corner again.
I've got another tough kick.
Oh, we're not worried about his kicking out tonight.
Look at that.
Nine from nine, 100%.
Mr. 100%.
I hope we haven't done it yet.
Richie Ngwange, this one does stay very left this time.
So his first miss, Coles' try goes unconverted,
but it's New Zealand 68th, it's leading.
So just look at that, Kane just straightens up,
goes in, Odogwu gets sucked in a little bit,
even though there was another defender there.
But of course there's the man, the veteran Dane Coles,
just taking the pass and smiling
as he cruises over the line.
Beautiful.
Rico Ioane will bring this back for New Zealand.
And it's a doubly intense try.
Use it!
Boyguard sends it up with his good left boot that he has.
A couple of wats so underneath this,
he's got Ioane with him.
Can't be seen back there as well,
but Ioane's been dangerous with ball in hand.
No way through this time.
Nicola Canone ducks under one,
and that's the get stuck in attitude.
Itali has got from their replacement,
has bricks, he's been good straightening up.
Peeling off some good meters in this passenger play, Itali.
Fiverr in close for Canone again.
Tashrello under pressure as well to clear away.
No way through though.
Delia, who has just held him up with brute strength
in New Zealand, going to win this ball back.
And we'll have a couple of changes for New Zealand now.
With Damian McKenzie coming on,
he's going to replace Richie Monga.
And we've also got Anton Lina Brown, who's going to come on.
And it looks like he's coming on to replace Jordi Barrett.
Jordi Barrett's been out of the tournament
with a knee problem, and they'll be pleased to see that,
because I think it's one that has caused them concern.
And that man had a little bump in the week,
so maybe a little precaution there, taking him off.
Because else, if you miss one kick and you get pulled,
it's a tough old school, that one.
Damian McKenzie was brilliant last week.
And that big win against Namibia.
Real fleet of foot, brings another attacking dimension
to this all-black team.
Crouch!
The Roygaard-Mckenzie combination was excellent
against Namibia.
A couple of tries apiece, a few assists each as well.
New Zealand's scrum again is dominating,
it's controlled beautifully,
in the back by Saviour, here is Roygaard,
put the knee up.
Roygaard scoops it up, Leonard Brown, his first touch.
Offload there for Kane, shuffles it along.
Overhead pass, McKenzie spins a beautiful full wide
for Will Jordan with his pace.
Back and field for McKenzie, slips out of one,
still alive for Bowdoin Barrett.
New Zealand leaving Italian defenders in their wake, Roygaard.
Leonard Brown for Scott Barrett.
The Scott Barrett up over the 22.
New Zealand soaring through the line
and then it comes undone with a clean drop from Sam Kane.
Oh, there's just so much desire to run that ball forward,
to run into space, to pick good lines, to offload.
McKenzie, look at this for a pinpoint pass.
Out on the outside, Jordan with a little inside ball.
McKenzie almost away.
Just a shame about the little error eyes up.
That was probably the best goal of the game.
Okay, yeah, that's fine.
More changes for Italy.
We've got Simone Ferrari who's gonna come back on
to replace Marco Riccioni.
And also we've got Toa Halafihi, former Hurricanes player,
on to replace Michele Lamaro, captain now.
Yeah, come on, let's go.
Looked a bit dejected in there, Michele Lamaro,
he's good captain of this Italian team.
Well out high hopes, didn't they, before the game?
Just got smoked in there, first half.
Defensive ways, the line out was a problem.
From the 17th minute onward,
they just conceded every few minutes.
Just impossible to come back from that sort of defensive error.
Somebody's Savio at the back,
as again they shove on once more, New Zealand.
Just rolling forward and there goes Savio once more.
Canaan support, two of the leaders.
Here's the veteran white lock, New Zealand penalty.
It's another storming run from the captain, Adi Savab.
He's had a huge game tonight, he's got two tries,
but he's run good lines, he's made good decisions,
he's gone around from the back of the mall when it's counted,
he's come at pace, he's got a good lead,
he's got a good lead, he's got a good lead,
when it's counted, he's come at pace,
deciding on the scrub now,
this is a team that just want more and more and more.
Big crowd here, we talked about this,
Leon Stadium being a Pax of the Rafters,
57,083 number of fans in here tonight,
we can hear every single one of them.
They're having a blast.
That lock particularly,
a lot of New Zealand fans have traveled here,
being an influx in Leon.
Grouch!
Point!
Six!
Away come New Zealand once more,
a little flick ball from Leonard Brown to McKenzie,
looking to accelerate, spin and falling over the line.
The connections in communication are superb,
an Italian scatter once more.
Quite all and nobody easy.
Oh, yeah!
There's a handful, he's got great pace,
he's got great strength, but not even he himself
would expect to get through this easy,
I guess another international team,
a missed tackle, slides his way over,
loads of pace, McKenzie, look at this,
into the gap he goes.
Gobbisi with a missed tackle,
it's not one the Italian defense
will wanna look at on Monday again.
McKenzie, oh, it's perfect,
converts his own try from wide
to extend New Zealand's advantage now,
75 points to 10.
Well, a man who lit the place up in 1987
in that rugby World Cup win.
Give us a wave, JK.
No, he's aging.
Nice, he's a grumpy man at times, isn't he?
You'd think he'd be smiling now at 73 points to 10.
Well, he does have such close ties to Italy as well,
family there and was coached Italy.
I think Jeff Wilson had a bigger smile on his face,
didn't he?
What have Italy got in these all final,
knock on advantage,
he head towards the final throws,
they've lost the ball and Will Jordan
is streaking away again,
send her and kick back and field the bounce
for Adi Savir, the offload for Jordan,
they've got it on a string.
Well, when it's not going your way,
the bounce of the ball will defy you as well
and that's exactly what's happened.
Era from Italy, a little chip over the top,
the bounce horrendous for the defensive team.
Just trying so hard to make it happen,
the Italians and the era coming.
Thank you, bro.
Will Jordan with a little kick over the top,
the ever-present Adi Savir jumps up into,
and look at this for a little offload.
Boy, he's been everywhere tonight, Savir.
Will Jordan for all his work, finally gets reward.
For the second time, I should say.
He has started it off in the opening five minutes,
Will Jordan, and now, gee,
we're still 10 minutes to play here,
and the score hitting 80.
Italy need to find some reserves in the final 10 minutes.
McKenzie picks up where Richard Munger left off,
and New Zealand go out to 82 points to 10.
Lovely little kick over the top, wasn't it?
And just look at the big man,
he's playing an integral role in pretty much every play
of this encounter.
Adi Savir has just been outstanding.
Final pass, Jordan goes over.
And they're up to 82 points.
McKenzie sends it down to Kopowotso.
Sends the kick up high again,
McKenzie will come forward to Kopowotso to chase,
it's a good chase too from Kopowotso,
but McKenzie got there first.
Pellea.
Tackle.
Bent back in this tackle.
Dane Coles.
Bodum Barrett, should kick over the top,
playing in it first, receive a Kopowotso,
rather it's Ioane who comes forward,
and he's got great feet in the acceleration,
chopped down by Kane.
The back for Breck,
a little bit of space here for Italy,
oh, found the hole,
but Maurizio's center partner eventually scooped it up,
did well in the end, ball goes to ground,
and it's just unraveling for Italy,
and New Zealand look to absolutely punish again here.
Up the middle, Barrett for Ioane,
bounced on for McKenzie,
McKenzie weaving him, jinking his way to the line,
just stopped in his tracks.
Roy Gadbutelea for Barrett,
big wide ball over the top of Sam Whitelaw,
but a penalty for New Zealand still,
got a Harlem Globetrotters feel now.
Yeah, exactly, it's all razzmatazz,
it's all showing up, tap and go.
Tap and go for Will Jordan,
court just short.
Offense is right.
Bowden Barrett will get him and clear away.
Ioane, Coles in the opposite corner,
Dane Coles on the left,
and Dane Coles on the right,
and New Zealand's score in 13th try.
Well, it's all too easy now, it's capitulation.
It's the Italians holding their heads down,
I guess, and a little bit of embarrassment now,
the scoreboard ticking away,
it's not something they envisaged,
certainly not something they planned on or wanted.
It has gone a little awry,
it's gone a little pear-shaped,
and the scoreboard is just telling
an awful story for them.
Dane Coles, second little march in, untouched.
Yeah.
So much talk, that Italy had closed the gap,
they thought they'd made those big strides,
you hadn't played New Zealand for a couple of years,
but it's the greats watch on.
It's that true marker of where they are at
and where they need to be.
Yeah, before the game,
you said they needed to put down the marker,
I said they needed to bounce back,
they've done both, haven't they?
The Old Wax do consider themselves
as one of the favourites for Rugby World Cup 23,
and this certainly is a little warning sign,
shot across the bar to all the other teams.
Taking all his time,
Damian McKenzie making the most of it as well.
Yeah.
For Kieran Crowley, who won a World Cup with New Zealand
in 1987, it's a difficult day for him
as the coach of Italy.
89 points to 10 now.
And another penalty, it's been a clinic.
It's been a real clinic,
it's been a polished performance from the whole
of this Old Black squad of 23.
Started off with the Jordan try,
it was then Aaron Smith's show for a little while,
how good was he?
Just controlled things, dived in the mall,
scored a try, Mark Talaise has been outstanding on the wing,
he's counted, he's taken every opportunity,
but that man there, Adi Sevier, has led from the front.
Couple of tries, loads of kicks,
couple of tries, loads of carries, couple of assists,
he's made the right decisions, he's run good lines all night.
He is our MasterCard player of the match.
Thank you.
Over 50.
Brought down by Sam Whitelock,
the Old Black's all-time appearance leader,
now as Roy Gutt cuts a path and straight up the middle,
accelerating the halfback and ball back in field,
Leonard Brown, Anton Leonard Brown in support.
Gets another one for the Blacks.
Well, you said it, it's a clinic.
Around the corner, the inside ball,
oh my God, he's got some pace, doesn't he?
Off he goes.
Realises he's not gonna get there,
times the inside pass brilliantly.
Anton Leonard Brown runs a good line.
Try number 14.
It's a rout.
Anton Leonard Brown adds his name to the list.
New Zealand make it 96.
Four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
Well, that was 101 one year, wasn't it?
1999, I think it was.
We looked it up a little earlier.
Could well get there again.
Oh, Sam Kane in the air, comes off the head,
so it's gonna be balls for Italy.
Still having a crack here.
No way through Monti Ioane.
Nicola Canone's added something off the bench
for them coming on at half time.
Breaks.
Creating space for Ioane and here's Paolo O'Goglu,
real power runner.
Dragged down by Leonard Brown.
Good competition.
Pasrello will dig it out and clear away.
Shoveled along the line and now,
eventually it's Breaks again.
Still some effort and endeavour in Italy.
Just finding a struggle to get their way through.
Zuliani it was that time.
New Zealand playing with 14 at the moment.
Brodie Ritalik to the side, here goes Copparozzo.
As Italy pour forward, just dragged down
and a good tackle, five metres short of the line.
Pick and go from Italy.
New Zealand desperately trying to defend their line
late in the match.
Neck roll 10 wide.
Copparozzo and they're gonna blow this up.
You heard the TMO, there was a neck roll in there
from Paolo Gobbisi.
The time was on on the outside.
Could have been a great way to finish,
but here's the little neck roll.
Realised he was doing it, Gobbisi,
and let go but too late.
That's another crack clearance, isn't it?
Hardly severe, the man over the top contesting.
There's the release but too little, too late.
Nice break.
So Brodie Ritalik's gone to the side
and New Zealand had cleared the bench.
He's sitting down there pretty cuffed to be out.
He wouldn't be surprised if it's a little bit of cramp or.
New Zealand, five.
Probably fatigue.
He hasn't had a full 80 minutes.
New Zealand, five.
As we head towards the final minutes.
96 on the board.
Brought down by Sam Whitelock, milestone man.
Anton Lennart-Brown.
Scott Barrett, and another big shift from Scott Barrett.
Roy Goudle spread back out to the right for New Zealand.
The hands are quick, Mackenzie is quick.
That's cracked up high.
Play on, says the referee, nothing is yet.
Here's Whitelock up over the 22.
Kane looked to shift it on.
No, no, eight.
The ball instead and then they go once more.
The Whitelock, Mackenzie, the hands are quick.
Savvier is good too and then the little step
and Jink a bit of power, the offload for Dane Cole.
Couldn't quite hold onto it.
Tackle.
Just broke down as Dane Cole and Artie Savvier
combined once more.
And now Italy from behind their own sticks.
And got some numbers wide.
Brex puts it to the toe for Adoglu to chase.
Mackenzie sweeping across for New Zealand,
losing control of it.
Play on here for Italy and one Ignacio Brex.
And they might get something out of this at the end, Italy.
As New Zealand scramble back.
Gavisi just shoves it on from a standing start.
Favre, Hans-Willi Arnie, always combative, the Jersey 20.
No, no.
Cole's trope to get out of it.
Pass Rello, sizes up the options.
Now battling away, Italy.
Reloading each time.
Flat across the face, the hands are good.
Adoglu stepping inside to Lea, can't get past him.
Brilliant from Ioanni and Monti Ioanni for the corner.
The little hit and spin after the fabulous handling
and the tries given for Monti Ioanni.
Well, what a way to finish.
It's been a disappointing evening.
But the little continuity, the build up,
the patience in attack from this Italian side,
right at the end.
Excellent and the finish from Monti Ioanni.
Well under enormous pressure in the tackle,
he has found a way into that corner.
Brave as well to play from their own goal line.
McKenzie couldn't control.
Brex was on and he's had a good game, Brex actually.
It's all well tackled by this opposite number.
Oh.
Has he grounded it?
That's gonna be the big question.
No, the grounding happens before his foot goes into touch.
The foot is in the air initially as the ball is grounded.
So we can award the try.
You can award the try.
It's a try.
The ball is grounded while his foot is in the air
and then his foot goes down, okay?
Well, the try is given.
Right on the line.
Just reward for a courageous final moment.
Thank you.
For Ridley.
Conrad Smith knows a good try when he sees one.
And he knows the spirit of the game, doesn't he?
Come on to Ioannis.
Some really good injections.
Thank you everyone.
In the second half.
Deserves a nice finish as well.
Paolo Garbisi will have the final act of the match.
The conversion is wonderful.
But the All Blacks have put on a show in Lyon
on a milestone night for Sam Whitelock
as he becomes the most kept All Black of all time.